my.jobs 2013-11-26

# Privacy policy for My.jobs

This Privacy Policy covers the collection, use and disclosure of information collected through the My.jobs and Universe.jobs websites, owned and operated by DirectEmployers Association (hereafter, “DE”, “We”, “Us”). It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. 

DirectEmployers Association has been awarded TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy policy and practices have been reviewed by TRUSTe for compliance with [TRUSTe's program requirements](http://www.truste.com/privacy-program-requirements/) including transparency, accountability and choice regarding the collection and use of your personal information. The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through the My.jobs and Universe.jobs websites and does not cover information that may be collected through any mobile applications, devices or third party affiliates and partners. 

TRUSTe's mission, as an independent third party, is to accelerate online trust among consumers and organizations globally through its leading privacy Trustmark and innovative trust solutions. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [privacy@my.jobs](mailto:privacy@my.jobs). If you are not satisfied with our response you can contact [TRUSTe here](http://watchdog.truste.com/pvr.php?page=complaint)

### Information Collection and Use

We collect the following personal information from you when you visit our websites or sign up to use the My.jobs Service: 

  * Contact information such as name, email address, mailing address, phone number
  * Company name and address
  * Unique Identifiers such as user name, account number, password
  * Resume information, such as work history, education, and military service

  We use this information to: 

  * Register you for an account
  * Administer your account
  * Assess the needs of your business to determine suitable products
  * Send you requested service information
  * Respond to customer service requests
  * Send you a newsletter
  * Send you marketing communications
  * Respond to your questions and concerns
  * Improve our website and marketing efforts
  * Conduct research and analysis

### Information Sharing

We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell, rent or otherwise distribute your personal information to third parties. 

##### The My.jobs Platform

We share your job search activity and profile data with employers with whom you have interacted via our services. Employers may use your job search activity and profile data to send you messages, such as job opportunities, hiring events, career fairs, and general information about their company. Employers may also export your profile data to load into career marketing, customer relationship management, and applicant tracking systems. You may opt-out or decline such sharing of information by updating your [account settings](https://secure.my.jobs/account/edit/). 

##### Service Providers

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as offering customer service or sending emails. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us and are contractually obligated to keep your information confidential. 

##### Legal Disclaimer

We may also disclose your personal information:

  * as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process
  * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request
  * if DE is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information
  * to any other third party with your prior consent to do so

### User Access and Choice

If your personal information changes, you may correct, update, amend, remove, or ask to have it removed by making the change on your user [account settings](https://secure.my.jobs/account/edit/) page or by submitting a service request via the My.jobs [Contact](https://secure.my.jobs/contact/) page. You may deactivate or delete your account from the account settings page at any time, or contact us directly. We will respond to your request within 30 days. 

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

##### Opt-out Preferences

If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop receiving our newsletter or marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your account settings page or you can contact us via the My.jobs [Contact](https://secure.my.jobs/contact/) page. 

##### Tracking Technologies / Cookies

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user’s computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on our sites to identify and track visitors, their usage of our websites, and their website access preferences across multiple requests and visits. We link the information we store in cookies to personally identifiable information you submit while on our site. 

We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” directory. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but the functionality of some areas of our site will be limited. 

##### Web Beacons / Pixels

The analytics service we employ uses a software technology called clear pixels (a.k.a. Web Beacons), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear pixels are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online activities of website users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user’s computer hard drive, clear pixels are embedded invisibly on web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We tie the information gathered by clear pixels to your personally identifiable information. 

##### Analytics / Log Files

As is true of most websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We do not link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information. 

##### 3rd Party Tracking

The use of tracking technologies by our service providers, technology partners or other 3rd party assets (such as social media) on the site is not covered by our privacy policy. These 3rd parties may use cookies, clear pixels, images, and scripts to help them better manage their content on our site. We do not have access or control over these technologies. We do not tie the information gathered to your personally identifiable information. 

##### Behavioral Targeting / Re-Targeting

We may partner with a third party ad network to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our ad network partner uses cookies and Web beacons to collect non-personally identifiable information about your activities on this and other websites to provide you targeted advertising based upon your interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you targeted ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads. 

### Security

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as your username and password) in our log-in portal, we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). 

We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our website, you may contact us using the My.jobs Contact page. 

### Additional Information

##### Links to 3rd Party Sites

Our sites include links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from those of DE. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any website you visit. 

##### Testimonials

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you may contact us using the My.jobs Contact page. 

##### Social Media Widgets

Our website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button, links to our various social media pages and Widgets, such as the Share This button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our site. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

##### Changes To This Policy

We may update this privacy policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.
